Guys, in this video we are going to talk about
Punjab National Bank. If you
already have an account in Punjab National Bank or you are going to
open your account in Punjab National Bank,
then please keep
watching this video completely because
in this video we are going to do a detailed review of Punjab National Bank.
We
will know how Punjab National Bank is,
how many branches it has, how many ATM machines it has,
what kind of service is available in this bank,
if we open our account
and ever go to the branch, then how quickly
our work gets done,
what is the behavior of the branch employees, what
kind of charges are levied in this bank,
which accounts are available for us in this bank, whether we get a
zero balance account or
not, whether we will get a credit card
or not, many such
questions will be in your mind, all those
questions are going to be cleared in this video,
let's start
this video and understand all the
information about Punjab National Bank.
Hello, my name is Manish Prajapati, welcome you all
once again to a new video.
If you have come to the channel for the first time, please
subscribe. If you like the video then  Please do
like. So guys, if we talk about
Punjab National Bank, then Punjab
National Bank is the second largest bank in the government sector.
This bank has more than 180 million
customers and has more than
12,000 branches across India and
more than 13,000 ATM machines. Like all other banks,
Punjab National Bank also has a guarantee of up to ₹1 lakh for you.
According to DICGC, your ₹1
lakh here is 100% secure.
Although it is a government bank, I have given you this information.
If we talk about the products in Punjab National Bank,
what
type of products are available in which bank? Look, it is a
government bank, it is a very old bank, so
inside this bank you get almost all types of
products, like you
can open your savings account here.
In this bank you get many savings accounts of
different types. Otherwise, if
you want to open a current account here, then
you also get a current account in this bank.
Apart from this, you can
also open a salary account
in this bank. If you  If you want to open an account,
you
also get zero balance accounts in this bank. This bank
basically has three zero balance accounts,
one of which is the BS BDA account and the second Samman
account. This is also a zero balance account that you
can open. If you open a salary account,
it also opens with a zero balance. So, in
this way,
you get three accounts with zero balance.
Otherwise, if you want to open any other account,
you will have to
maintain a minimum balance accordingly. Basically, if I
tell you about the minimum balance here,
if your branch is located in a rural area, then
you have to maintain a minimum balance of ₹5000000
and in metro and urban areas, you have to maintain a
minimum balance of ₹1000000 in your account in this bank.
This balance can vary depending on the account. Punjab
National Bank has its own credit cards,
so if you open an account in this bank,
your
chances of getting a credit card increase. At the same time,
you also get all types of loans in Punjab National Bank.
You can easily get a
personal loan for business here.
You can get a loan and a home loan from this bank at a
very good interest rate. You get the
loan facility here. If you have
opened an account in this bank and are
maintaining it well, then it is possible that
you will start getting
credit card and loan offers from this bank on a pre-approved basis.
If you want to invest in Punjab National Bank, then you
can open your FD or RD here.
Apart from this, if you
want to do SIP etc. in mutual funds, then that
is also available in this bank. You can do all this.
Like every other bank,
Punjab National Bank also provides the benefit of all types of government schemes like PM Suraksha Bima Yojana or Jan Dhan Yojana. Apart from this, Atal Pension Yojana, all these government schemes are available in banks, you can find them in Punjab National Bank.
Let
us talk about the services once.
If you are opening an account in Punjab National Bank,
any of your own, then you
get a lot of services here, like first of all,
you can use net banking on your account here.
Apart from this, you can get mobile banking service in this bank.
Mobile banking and net
banking services are very important in every bank.
Here you can do many of your banking work
sitting at home, such as
taking out a statement or checking balance
or transferring money through IMPS RTGS or checking
debit card etc.
You get all these services
inside PNB. PNB has a
separate application called PNB One. After opening the account, if you
download it,
you get the benefit of all the services
sitting at home. Apart from this, you
can link this bank with any UPI app and use it for your
UPI transactions.
Apart from this,
this bank has recently started its WhatsApp2 banking, in
which you can use
WhatsApp-web. To open an account in PNB,
your age should be 18 years plus.
You should be an Indian citizen and
you should have Aadhar card and PAN card in
original, then you can open the account.
Otherwise, even if your age is not 18 years plus,
you will be able to open the account.  But for that
you will need your parent's documents and will have to
go to the branch to open the account.
Now let's talk about the account opening
process and how
we can open an account in this bank. See,
in this bank you get the facility to open an account in two ways,
first online and
second offline. If you want to open an account online,
then you
can open an account from the official website of this bank.
There you
can open all the accounts online. If your video verification is done here, then you will
not have to go to the branch,
all your work will be done online.
But if you are going to open an account online
in this bank, then
you may also face a problem here, in which if you
do a video verification here, then the
video verification is not done very quickly. My
verification was done here in 3 days, so this is
a big issue. Otherwise, if you
want to open an account offline, then you
can open your account by going to any PNB bank and
take your Aadhar card and PAN card with you there. Your
account will be opened easily. If we talk about  Let's talk about the
charges in this bank,
what are the charges levied in this bank
for us, so see, in almost every bank
you must be aware that some charges are similar,
so the first charge here is of
debit card, if you open your account in this bank
then you will have to pay the
charge of debit card here and this
charge of debit card
is decided according to the variant of your debit card, which
debit card you are taking because the more the
facility in the debit card, the higher will be the
charge, the more the benefits, the
higher will be the charge you will have to pay,
if the debit card is of lower variant then
you get the debit card at a lower charge, so the
charges here depend on the person from whom you take the debit card, at least if
I talk about it then here you will have to pay a
charge according to the minimum balance of ₹1500000,
brother, if you maintain the balance in your account then
you will not have to pay any unnecessary charge for non-maintenance here,
apart from this, you
also have to pay the charge for SMS alert in this bank,
so here your same is debited every three months  A
charge of around ₹1 is deducted. Rest, see, there are
many types of charges in every bank. If
I tell you all the charges in this video, then the
video will become very long,
such as ECS charge, check bounce charge. If
you give a check and it bounces, then a
charge is deducted for it. So, there are
many such charges in every bank. If I
talk about check book, in this bank, you can
easily get all three documents - check book, passbook, debit card.
You will have to pay a charge for the debit card that you get from the branch. The
first check book that you have is free,
after that you will have to pay a charge and the
passbook is available for free once in a year.
Now let us talk about the
behavior of the branch employees.
Suppose we open an account in which bank
and after that, if we ever
go to our branch, then how quickly our
work gets done. Look, it is a government bank.
Here, you know that the
employees in government banks are government employees.
They do
not have any fear of their job, so they work a little loosely.
In government banks, there is a minimum  The
average balance has to be kept low, so
many people open accounts. These are government
banks, people trust them, so there is a
lot of crowd in government banks,
so you will have to manage a little here.
If your branch is too
crowded, you may have to
stand in line and it is possible that
your work may not be done many times in one go because there are
government employees, so brother,
you will have to manage a little here.
You will
not get the same service in this bank as private banks like HD
Bank, Kotakmahindrafinance.com.
So if you want to open an account in a government bank
and there is a branch of Punjab National Bank near you,
then you can open an account
because in this bank you
get a home branch, that is, the branch
in which your account is opened,
all your work will be done in that branch.
If you go to any other branch for any work, then
they will clearly refuse you, saying
that you should go to your home branch, so you have to
check how close the Punjab
National Bank branch is to you, because if the branch is far away, then
you will face problems.
Otherwise, if you want good service, that
means if any of you  If you need any work, then
all your work can be done on call,
talk to customer care and your cheque book
order, debit card order, you
want to do many things through mobile banking app, intentionally there is no need to go to the branch,
then instead of opening an account in this bank, you can
open an account in any private bank because the
customer care service is very bad, if you
call for any work, they will say brother,
go to the branch, rest their mobile banking
application and net banking run very slow,
apart from this there are many limited
services, then here you will have to go
to the branch to do almost all the work, keep
this in mind, rest you
can see as per your convenience, I
find Union Bank the best than PNB,
what is your opinion about the rest, please do tell by commenting